drivereasy.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy - Drivereasy.com - Driver Easy

Your privacy is important to us (“drivereasy.com”, “Driver Easy”, “we”, “us”, or “our”), so we have developed this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes our data privacy practices, including what types of your personal information are gathered, how we use and share the information, how we safeguard the information, and how you can delete or change the information.

This Privacy Policy applies to personal information collected by us through our product Driver Easy and our website drivereasy.com. By using the Driver Easy program, drivereasy.com or the services provided on the website, you agree to how we use your personal information stated in this Privacy Policy.

##  **What Personal Information We Collect and Why We Collect Them**

We may collect or ask for following information from you when you visit our website, purchase or use our product, and/or contact us by email or otherwise.

###  **Information We Collect When You Visit drivereasy.com**

We may collect your personal information when you visit our website drivereasy.com.

We may request your name and email address when you contact us using the contact form on the Contact Us, Resend License Key or Suggest Article Correction page. We need this information in order to get back to you shortly. Your IP address is logged by our system when you visit drivereasy.com so we can prevent spams, attacks or other malicious behaviors against our website.

We use the following technologies and services to improve our website user experience. And they may also collect your personal information.

####  **Cookies**

For drivereasy.com to work properly, we sometimes place small data files called cookies on your device.

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences over a period of time, so you don’t have to adjust them whenever you come back to the site or go from one page to another.

Drivereasy.com uses cookies to remember your actions and preferences in order to provide you with better services when you make return visits. Our cookies also store the language setting of your web browser so we can display the proper language to you. When you use your redeem code to get our product in our giveaways, our website also request your name and email address and store them in cookies. Every cookie drivereasy.com assigns to your device which accesses our servers is non-unique and non-identifiable. All drivereasy.com cookies are characterized as secure and non-invasive. The information that we collect is not used to identify you personally and the pattern data is fully under our control.

By using drivereasy.com, you agree to how we use cookies. If you don’t want cookies to be placed on your device, you can delete them and change your browser settings to prevent them from being placed. For details about how to delete or control cookies on your device, please consult the documentation of your web browser. Please note that if you disable cookies, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit drivereasy.com, and some services or functionalities of the website may not work.

We also use **Google AdSense** on drivereasy.com to support our website. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to drivereasy.com or other websites. You can visit this page for more information about [the vendors that are certified by Google ](https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/94149)for third-party ads. You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting[ Ads Settings.](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) Or you can opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/). 

#### **Third-party Tools**

#####  **Google Analytics**

We use a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about visitor behavior on drivereasy.com. Google Analytics collects information about what pages the visitors visit, how long the visitors are on the website, how the visitors get to the website and what the visitors click. Google Analytics collects only visitors’ IP address, rather than their personal information that can identify who they are (like their names and addresses). The processing and sharing of your personal data by Google Analytics is governed by Google’s privacy policies. We use your information collected by Google Analytics to improve our website so that we can provide you with better experience, and we do not use it for other purposes.

Google Analytics places a cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique visitor the next time you visit our website, but the cookie is only under control of Google. You can disable cookies on your browser to prevent Google Analytics from identifying you when you come back to drivereasy.com. You can also install [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) on your web browser to prevent your data from being collected by Google Analytics.

#####  **Disqus**

We use a comment hosting service called “Disqus” to host the comments you leave on drivereasy.com. Disqus may collect your name, email address, IP address and so on when you create an account and/or post a comment. They don’t share this personal information with us except the name you submit. What information they collect and how they collect it are subject to their own [privacy policy](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717103-disqus-privacy-policy) and [terms](https://help.disqus.com/en/articles/1717102-terms-of-service), and we suggest you should check them for more details about their processing of your personal information.  

#####  **reCAPTCHA**

We have implemented reCAPTCHA v3 on drivereasy.com. This is a service by Google that helps us fight spam and abuse on our website. It collects your hardware and software information, such as device and application data, and sending these data to Google for analysis. The information collected will be used for improving reCAPTCHA and for general security purposes. It will not be used for personalized advertising by Google. Your use of reCAPTCHA v3 is subject to the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) and [Terms of Use](https://policies.google.com/terms?hl=en). You may need to check them for more information about how reCAPTCHA works and how it collects and processes your data.

####  **Links To Other Websites**

Our website includes links to other ones, whose privacy practices may differ from those in drivereasy.com. If you access other websites using the links provided, they may collect personal information from you. The processing of your information is governed by their privacy statements. We do suggest you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

###  **Information You Submit When Placing Orders**

Driver Easy collects your personal information when you place an order. 

We use a third-party ecommerce platform, **2Checkout** , to handle your billing on our behalf. This ecommerce platform may request your information, including your name, home or working address, phone number, email address, and payment information such as your credit card number, expiration date, security code, etc. This information is used to process your payments, delivering services and the like. The handling and processing of your information on 2Checkout are subject to its privacy policies and terms of use.

2Checkout may transmit some of your personal information to us when placing orders. This information include what are mentioned in the last paragraph EXCEPT your payment information, such as your credit card number, expiration date, security code, etc. We collect your information in order to fill your orders and to better deliver our services. We will also use this information to contact you if we have trouble processing an order. We do not use your personal information for purposes other than those mentioned above.

###  **Information Collected When You Use Driver Easy**

When you use Driver Easy to scan your computer, the program collects your hardware information, your MAC (media access control) address, and your operating system information. Driver Easy send all these data back to our servers. With this information, Driver Easy can identify your hardware devices, and we can deliver you the correct drivers that are suitable for your devices and your operating system. This information is also used for any technical, product, or customer support request. 

We also use **Google Analytics** to collect the information about your behavior on Driver Easy. We collect the unique identifier of your computer and send it to Google Analytics for analysis. We use the SHA-2 algorithm to encrypt this identifier when sending it so it cannot be cracked and recognized by others. This information is only used by Google Analytics to identify you as an anonymous individual user. Google Analytics also collects the information of your IP address, your language and country (detected using your IP address), your operating system information, your screen resolution and what program screen you are on. We use all the information only to improve Driver Easy and provide our users with better experience. We do not store or share this information. And please note that how Google collects and processes your data is subject to their privacy statements. We encourage you to review those statements in order to have a better understanding of how your personal data is used.

##  **Why Driver Easy Collects Your Personal Information**

We collect your personal information in order to provide you with better services and user experience when you visit our website, purchase and/or use Driver Easy. We do not use your personal information to make automated decisions. We do not disclose your personal data to any third-party individual or organization. 

## **How We Store and Secure Your Personal Information**

We have multiple security measures in order to avoid the loss, misuse and alteration of your personal information and make sure it is under our control. The personal data we keep are stored on a server located outside the EU. This server is located in a controlled facility and only authorized personnel have access to the database of personal information. We have also set up a high security-level firewall so that we can keep your personal data secure.

##  **How You Can Change or Remove Your Personal Information**

Providing your personal information is not mandatory. You can contact us to remove your personal information from our database. You can check the final section of this Privacy Policy for our contact information. But please be aware that, because your personal information may be necessary for us to deliver our services, we may not be able to make these services available to you if your information is removed.

##  **How Often We Change This Privacy Policy**

We may modify or update this Privacy Policy from time to time according to user feedbacks and changes to privacy regulations. When we make changes to this Policy, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this Policy. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy periodically to know what changes we have made. You agree to the changes we made by continue visiting drivereasy.com, using Driver Easy and/or the other services we provide after the changes to this Privacy Policy.

##  **How You Can Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement or our privacy practices, or if you want to remove your personal data, please contact [support@drivereasy.com](http://www.drivereasy.com/contact-us/)
